Humans thrive off the feeling of
progress. [music] And that's why video
games are addicting. It's really hard to
feel like your life is going anywhere if
you don't have the feeling of progress.
To have the [music] feeling of progress,
like one thing is like noticing that you
have a feeling of progress or even just
having a growth mindset. Like everything
you do, you have the like intentionality
of trying to get better at it. And if
you're getting better at something every
single day, you're going to feel
extremely motivating in life. I remember
one thing that I did when I was starting
my channel trying to gain that sense of
momentum is I would write down every
single day like what is a new thing that
I tried or new thing that I learned and
when I looked back on this list every
single day like when I was writing the
next one it was motivating for me to
know that I was literally making
progress. I also would write down how
many subscribers I was getting and see
like okay I'm actually making some
[music] some sort of progress here. This
is the mechanism that makes video games
addicting.